<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>opinions on Midnight Rain Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/tags/opinions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in opinions on Midnight Rain Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>rein@fedora.email (rein)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rein@fedora.email (rein)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 23:05:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/tags/opinions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>不妨换一个角度来读贾浅浅</title>
      <link>https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/post/bu-fang-huan-yi-ge-jiao-du-lai-du-jia-qian-qian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 23:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rein@fedora.email (rein)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/post/bu-fang-huan-yi-ge-jiao-du-lai-du-jia-qian-qian/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;当我们谈论贾浅浅的诗歌时我们在谈论什么？当她再一次被社会舆论捧上高峰时社会在凝视什么？近期贾浅浅因为入围了中国作协会名单，屎尿屁文学突然又如洪水般涌入了大众的视线，所及之处无不是民众对她的冷嘲热讽。于是我也去趁着热度瞻仰了一下那几首流传最广的诗歌。可能是因为已经有心理准备，我的第一反应不是惊讶亦或是嫌恶，而是一种极具官僚主义特色朋克的朦胧荒谬感。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;网络上对贾浅浅的正经争辩不论褒贬无非只有两个起点：她那个贼有名的爹贾平凹和她其他还能入眼的诗。前者从贾浅浅作为文二代的出圈为例批判了中国学术界裙带关系的泛滥以及权力的腐败对文艺创作的垄断，后者从文学的角度分析了收录在其作品集《椰子里的内陆湖》里的诗歌并得出结论虽然贾浅浅造诣不高，但也没有大家想象的那么不堪。我完全同意两边的说法，但从这个热点体现出的某一点令人回味无穷：我们作为看客其实是隔了两层膜在品读贾浅浅的诗的。第一层是贾浅浅之个体，第二层是贾浅浅之事件，之后才轮到贾浅浅之作品。作为中国知名作家的女儿，就算贾浅浅本人再才华横溢，也很难不作为父亲的影子苟延残喘着；互联网对猎奇的病态追求更是进一步将作者和作品粘合在了一起，反方向鼓励人们将对作品的嗤之以鼻投射到作者身上。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有趣的是，即使我们以新批评的作品本体论来看待贾浅浅的屎尿屁文学，价值上依然得不到任何提升。因为屎尿屁文学的直白叙述是对隐喻，结构，张力，修辞等各个元素的完全否定，作为一个客体是空洞而毫无意义的。如此一来，被剥离了作者背景和引申含义的诗歌被彻底除名，不再以诗歌的形式而存在，转而成为了一种模糊的意识形态。且不谈作者本人是怎么想的，但在我看来，贾浅浅的屎尿屁诗歌创作并不是纯粹的诗歌创作，而是一场注重于反诗歌创作的大型魔幻行为艺术。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;那么反诗歌又是一个什么新的名词？这一切都可以追溯回第一次世界大战期间诞生的艺术运动，达达主义。达达主义并非是某一类艺术流派的指代名词，而是一场通过挑战传统美学从而对社会价值观发起的无声挑衅，一个颠覆现代艺术标准对无意义和无秩序的无尽追求，也是一种反叛的精神和对美学的彻底瓦解。从某种意义上来说，达达主义的定义与当代所提出的嘻哈精神是相似的。两者虽都包含了艺术形式，但本质上是一种对生活以及社会的态度。也就是说，我们所需要关注的不是作为作品的艺术，而是作为结构的艺术；作品本身没有任何值得挖掘的引申意义，其价值存在于创作过程中对结构的破坏与在所存结构碎片上重新搭建的物体所象征的可能性，达到对既定标准的完全去中心化。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;说到达达主义，就不得不提到马赛尔·杜尚的《喷泉》。即使你没听说过这个艺术家或这件艺术作品，你肯定在网络上欣赏过它的图片。《喷泉》作为达达主义的代表作之一，不仅在主旨上与反艺术极为契合，其表达形式也十分尊重贾浅浅的美学：一个署名“R.MUTT”的小便池。艺术的定义是什么？艺术真的是伟大，纯净，而高雅的吗？一个合格的艺术品需要有什么元素？如果一个人无法完美的回答以上这些问题，又有什么资格去指责杜尚只是个哗众取宠的跳梁小丑呢？现代艺术向我们传达着这么一个概念：因为艺术是生成的，所以审美标准不应该被一个绝对的权威所垄断；比起一个作品的细节或者说它所体现出来的美术功底这些能以客观角度来衡量的元素，我们更应该注重于它的整体与表面之下隐藏着的理念。无论是杜尚的现成品艺术观念还是贾浅浅的屎尿屁文学，都是以叛逆为中心以粗俗为半径，紧紧环绕着现代社会的余孽朝那些早已目瞪口呆的权威们疯狂竖中指。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;让我们再把话题扯回诗歌。反诗歌这个名词并不是我个人的发明，而是由智利诗人尼卡诺尔·帕拉首先提出的。他所提议的“antipoemas”概念呼吁诗人抛弃传统诗歌的词藻堆砌，浪漫抒情，和所谓的韵味，并以直率的手法追求对现实的口语化描写。但与绝大多数后现代主义的产物相同，虽然帕拉自称为反诗人，他却无法完全定义反诗歌。与彻底粉碎既定概念的达达主义不同，反诗歌运动的立场并不是以破坏为奠基对现实进行的反抗，而是通过讽刺的力量来扭曲已知的现实。换一种说法，达达主义是艺术的终点站，强迫艺术家们停留在原地围绕着艺术的理念进行自我反思；反诗歌是艺术的延续，允许诗人们跳出文学体裁所限制的框架自由创作，前提是不能脱离诗歌的宗旨本身。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;贾浅浅的屎尿屁文学始于达达主义的理念，终于反诗歌的方法。作品集里对污秽物的大量引用呼应了杜尚将小便池送入美术馆展厅的魔幻行为，平铺直叙的文字凸显出了反诗歌的一大特点反诗意。然而有一点值得注意：贾浅浅作为知名作家的女儿，其身份与达达主义艺术家并不相符。如果说达达主义是民众站在外部对于作为他者的权威的解构，那么贾浅浅主义便是权威站在内部对权威的自我解构。放在中国的形式主义大环境来看，贾浅浅对荧幕的破坏象征着体系的完全胜利与同时之于权威和平民之上的优越，而荧幕后目瞪口呆的观众就是当代社会规训权力的最佳养料。贾浅浅这场大型行为艺术的成功，无论是世俗意义还是网络影响上，都代表着对系统的蔑视。系统的自我审视却不会如达达主义所期待的那样在结构崩溃后逐渐完成对艺术的去中心化，而是朝着反方向倒退，加固且加速艺术的中心化和排外化趋势。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;从文学的角度上来说，贾浅浅的作品也许一文不值。但从社会意义上来看待的话，这场荒唐的闹剧何尝不是一个伟大的实验呢？你又有什么自信心一口咬定文学的界定线呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;写这篇文章的时候我陷入了一种迷茫。这到底算是正八经的严肃讨论呢，还是瞎编乱造的shitpost呢？我原先是抱着魔征乐子人的心态来调侃贾浅浅的，可写着写着我似乎也被自己的话术困住了，仿佛贾浅浅真的是什么21世纪中国的精神领袖，后现代主义的革命先驱。我作为作者的使命已经到此结束了，或者如巴特所说，我已经被杀死了。至于这篇文章的属性到底是什么就当课后练习吧，还请读者们自行判断。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Happiness </title>
      <link>https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/post/on-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 11:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rein@fedora.email (rein)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/post/on-happiness/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know how most of those low-quality mass produced articles and your cynical high school essays titled &amp;ldquo;On xxx&amp;rdquo; usually begin with the template &amp;ldquo;what is xxx exactly? according to Wikipedia/Meriam-Webster, xxx means [insert Ctrl+p], in other words, [insert paraphrases]&amp;rdquo;? It is considered a cliché attention grabber yet also the safest as immature attempts at starting an essay revolving around a specific noun either results in seemingly sophisticated pseudo-philosophical jargon or modern poetry tier coerced metaphorization and lyricism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exploration and analysis of happiness from the unprofessional side has encountered this dilemma in the same bizarre way writers encounter on the quest for a good and cringe-free hook. Endeavors at deciphering happiness from the subjective perspective will all end up in the following four categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Life Appreciator: avoids giving definitions and offers generic self-help advices on eating healthy, enjoying nature, spending time with family and friends, and finding beauty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Word Nerd: borrows big words from philosophy and literature to sound fancy while defining happiness to be &amp;ldquo;be happy with yourself&amp;rdquo; and expanding it into a list of adjectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Riddle Speaker: the life appreciator who relies heavily in unnecessary figurative languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Depressed Doomer: &amp;ldquo;there is no happiness&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not meant to be a satirical piece, nor do I withhold any objection toward people who try to define happiness as you will see how I would eventually be ridiculed by my own words very soon. I actually do agree with the idea that happiness the experience, or the perception, is completely subjective yet the elements involved in the concept itself can be objectified to a certain extent. What defines happiness? What are the elements of it? How do we pursue it? I would like to discuss these three questions in the following post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-definition&#34;&gt;The Definition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was motivated to write this post because of a random thought on the difference between the Chinese words 幸福 (xing fu) and 快乐 (kuai le). They all translate to &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo; in English yet 快乐 represents the temporary emotion of happiness stemming from a specific event, while 幸福 is a continual state of mind as in the word &amp;ldquo;contentment&amp;rdquo;. It is easy to understand temporary happiness, the product resulting from a relationship of cause and effect. A mentally healthy person experiences it through positive events like spending time with pets, playing an interesting game, or getting a satisfying job. However, as an emotion, temporary happiness will eventually pass its expiration date. General happiness in comparison serves as a perspective of life, a maturely established worldview, and a constant state of satisfaction with both oneself and the surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without further separating the implications and elements of these two feelings, a common misinterpretation of them perceives lasting happiness to be a collection of temporary happiness and can be maximized through being constantly exposed to stimulation. The phrase &amp;ldquo;happiness is a choice&amp;rdquo; is a demonstration of this confusion, as only temporary happiness can be a voluntary act and it cannot be accumulated to generate the more abstract sense of contentment, or general &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo; that most people refer to as. Temporary happiness is an absolute emotion that can only be described and grasped through comparison with its opposite emotions. One cannot experience any temporary emotions without learning their counterpart, otherwise the mind would subconsciously routinize these emotions to the extent where pain is no longer pain, or happiness is no longer happiness, but resembling a straight line on a flat surface with no vertexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does happiness indicate an absence, an acknowledgement, or a refusal of pain? As mentioned above, I do consider temporary happiness an acknowledgement of pain and the presence of pain the necessary precondition. But do I believe the same for general happiness? I would argue for it involving a process of digesting pain: acknowledgement first, nonchalance second, and refusal third. Happiness is not a formula where one can create an imbalance through weighting more temporary happiness, but a contradictory and self-deceiving mindset that presents a mirage of illusional everlasting joy, where no perfect balances can be found. We, as imperfect beings, can nevertheless get close to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-elements&#34;&gt;The Elements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am only here to discuss the components of general happiness. They are ranked on a hierarchical structure that can only be achieved from the basis to the top and we shall go in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. a safe surrounding environment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one needs any proofs or evidences to admit that it is simply impossible to be happy in a toxic environment where the basic right of survival cannot even be guaranteed. Despite the non-permanence of traumatic events, or you can argue the opposite, an environment is a constant factor that sometimes manifests itself as perpetual and inescapable, negating the possibility of a better circumstance and invalidating any vague sense of hope. It forms an obnoxious inner-loop of self doubt and fear of the outside world that cannot be broken unless the environment itself shatters to pieces. Even the minimal positive aspect, usually the only guiding light, is shaded by the overwhelming negative state of the environment and an already damaged mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the reason we are naturally inclined to encourage the unfortunate ones who happen to be trapped in such a setting to leave, but not to have &amp;ldquo;good vibes&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;stay positive&amp;rdquo;. Individual positivity is a response to and appreciation of the already existent total positivity instead of a manufactured decision or a mental switch that can be turned on and off regardless of the situation. If even temporary happiness is proved to be near unattainable in an unhealthy environment, then it is safe to assume its opposite to be the foundation of any higher level happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. the presence of a healthy level of desire and expectation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;healthy&amp;rdquo; here is ambiguous and indicates a balance between desire and satisfaction with the current state. Many zealous religious followers and self-help authors who share a distorted taste of Buddhism advocate for a life completely detached from lusts and embrace enlightened emptiness as a rebellion toward the rising consumerism in the west. I am in no way an expert in Buddhism, not to mention all the different interpretations, yet in my understanding, Buddhism endorses mutualistic and philanthropic desires that aim to reduce overall sufferings or maintain mindfulness of the self and disapproves only of materialistic and sensual lusts that lead to the despair arising from their unachievability and one&amp;rsquo;s complete subordination to them. Most who claim to have achieved enlightened emptiness would get more help from a therapist than Buddha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I do promote for having a healthy level of desires regardless of their attached properties. Desire is not a shameful inner fantasy one should escape from, but a detailed manifestation of the reason we are still alive and a goal to keep us moving forward. Through desires, we are able to generate a temporary purpose, which would consequently lead to the creation of expectations, motivating us to look forward to a future event. On the contrary, the lack of expectation toward everything indicates a loss of will to exist and the pessimistic view of the future being predicable and banal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is illogical for anyone who is void of desires and favors the cynical conclusion to proceed to the next stage: establish relationships and find love. Interacting with new people signifies a change, yet what is the point of changing if our theoretical hermit is a ghost of the present and the past who loses the ability to imagine future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. establishment of healthy relationships with the ability to love and to be loved&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are social beings and establish identities through relations with each other. The so-called &amp;ldquo;identity&amp;rdquo;, should be classified based on each individual&amp;rsquo;s consciousness and I would go as far as for arguing that identity starts as a relative reflection of the self in relations with different people and results in a consistent shape as the self has observed itself through others&amp;rsquo; perspectives for a certain period of time; there is no self without others, so to speak. The process of connecting serves as a medium for emphasizing on the distinctive part and proving the transcendental existence of an individual, with the prerequisite of the relationship being a positive one, or it would result in the same as of social isolation: severe detachment from the reality and the failure to construct a mature self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relationships without love, not necessarily in the romantic context, hold little to zero value comparing to ones that do due to the emotional alienation resulting from the existence of boundaries. Being mentally ostracized from social groups resembles residing in a transparent shell, where all interactions are performed through a misty layer and thus diminishing their values in terms of building individuality. Love is intrinsic to a life full of enthusiasm and expectations; without its presence, we would no longer bear the responsibility of staying alive and optimistic, causing our existence to be a feeble one as once an individual purpose is lost, there can be hardly any exterior influences to sustain the will to maintain happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. an adequate amount of concentration toward those that are material and present&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We laugh at those spiritual petite bourgeoisies who read too much for their indulgence in abstraction and fragmented knowledge to be compatible with the limited reality they can perceive, yet too little to get back to the humdrum and apply them to perfect oneself. It is a common phenomenon you can observe in the self claimed nihilistic young generation, who are blindfolded by the truth of meaninglessness and refuse to observe any objects without summarizing and &amp;ldquo;deconstructing&amp;rdquo; them to the &amp;ldquo;essence&amp;rdquo;. Not to argue that their conclusion is wrong, but such remoteness from the reality is destined to be self-destructive when nothing holds physical importance and serves merely as a constructed symbol. The world is a finite and material place, and to bid farewell to it is to bond the self to an aloof and cynical attitude and a subjective reality filled by skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another factor contributes to unhappiness is the obsession, anxiety, or paranoia about the past or the future. Same with the one who thinks detached from the material, those who live detached from the present are also haunted by a subjective reality where specific objects and events are reorganized or amplified to be in harmony with an intense emotion or a theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to proceed any further if we cannot be conscious participants in an objective reality due to the inversion of priority, which is to put the abstract over the actual and theorizing the imperceptible over experiencing the perceivable. Even if the objective reality is a myth, according to the quantum physicists, it is still practicable to take the advice of focusing on what is in front of you ~and touching grass~.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. personal faith or individual purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now, our quest for happiness leaves the problem of existential crisis unsolved. How to obtain a meaning through meaninglessness? Or how to shift the perspective from humanity back to the individual to avoid such paradoxical pessimism? Or aim for the more abstract route, how to be happy as a finite being with free will who cannot truly obtain a meaning from the infinite universe? One solution is to accept our ignorance and preserve some humbleness, coercing the rebellious mind to be passionate about the absurd and to kiss the insipidity of a mundane life. Its counterpart, unsatisfied with volitional ignorance, is represented by the pursuit of a faith or a purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the faith and the purpose bestow an ultimate meaning to support and validate the existence of each individual despite the nihilistic answer provided by existence itself. They do not have to be sophisticated or display high morals, but rather absolute and maximize the range of aspiration. This is the reason why people remain obedient to religion in a secularized age, the systemized and historic practice of faith centered on the worship of an absolute power who loves equally and shall never betray, for comfort of the fear of the void. Some aspire to save the country, some aspire to cure diseases, and some aspire to live a tranquil life with whom they love. Purposes are neither a hierarchy nor ranked based on their contribution to humanity. If an irrational and fabricated passion for the repetition of life is the acceptance of ignorance, then the chase after faith or purpose is the attempt at penetrating the veil of ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether the outside of ignorance is more ignorance or spiritual enlightenment, the exploration itself already serves as a unique meaning. This could have been the top of the pyramid, yet we have to encounter another, and the final dilemma: how to cope with a reality that contradicts personal values and stop being negatively empathetic for the agony of others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. reconciliation of the objective reality with the subjective reality and a solution for the contradictory process of bypassing pain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elucidate this confusing description: objective reality is the observe reality we are physically at; subjective reality is the expected reality we have mentally constructed; and reconciliation is the process of harmonizing these two visions, usually incompatible and divergent, to a unified state where one would not be bothered by the ineptitude of the world to actualize one&amp;rsquo;s idealism. In simple words, it is the live-action of the phrase &amp;ldquo;everything is great, but I am still unhappy&amp;rdquo; after you complete the checklist for the other five elements. The unavoidability of the shift from self to all after acquiring material well-being is a curse upon the gift of empathy. Different from the emo teenagers described in the fourth element, the helplessness and hopelessness of those who are professionals at living an enthusiastic life is not a result of meaninglessness, but of vexation and dissatisfaction at the current state of the world and their mandatory participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reality is the maximal extension of the surrounding environment and thus becomes physically inescapable when a man decides to venture beyond the bubble of an untroubled and blissful life. The popularization of Internet has propagated this phenomenon further due to the unavoidable information overload that constantly trespasses our safety zone of a perceptible inner world and put burdensome responsibility of empathizing with those who are outsiders of our inner world upon us. We are no longer only miserable by, due to, or for ourselves, but also rather miserable by, due to, or for others from an omniscient perspective. This melancholy resulted from an imperfect world can be only healed through hypocrisy of a good cause or the self conviction that morally exempts a mortal man from serving justice and displaying virtues universally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The uncertainty of an unpromising future and unstable atmosphere also threatens the achievability of happiness for the same reason of residing in a generally depressing environment, whether specifically for an economic, political, or cultural cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get back to the question of pain. The process of bypassing pain is demonstrated by the alternating pattern of acknowledgement and refusal, with nonchalance as a transition, whether it&amp;rsquo;s for the self or others. We accept agony for its substantiated existence, deliberately ignore it for its unbearable weight upon realizing happiness, and finally deny it by deceiving ourselves that agony is only temporary. It might not be deceiving as an undeniable fact, though it&amp;rsquo;s still deceiving regarding the lasting consequence of this fact. Humans are fragile beings and tabula rasas polluted by accumulated negative stimulus. The entire argument for permanent happiness is merely a hypothesis overthrown by the presence of pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-pursuit&#34;&gt;The Pursuit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have ever paid a visit to a normie bookstore, you will usually notice a huge shelf with collections of self-help books that promise to unlock the key to happiness. The overwhelming amount and the overly similar content of these books illustrate an extremely high market demand for fast-food tier spiritual guidance as true happiness becomes a luxury in the modern society. I have trolled self-help more than enough in this post and I feel obligated to justify my ~autistic~ cynicism towards it: self-help books falsely portray happiness as the product redeemable through a certain procedure that can be quantified and manipulated; by labeling their generic and impractical advices as a door toward nirvana, most, but not all happiness-obsessed self-help authors are just hungry for some cash and bring nothing good other than producing a temporary contrived mental orgasm for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pursuit of happiness is pessimistic because pursuit is the realization of non-being. By participating in active pursuit of happiness, one has to be constantly conscious of their unhappiness, leading to the opposite of the intended purpose. From a personal perspective, unhappiness can be reduced by removing negative elements from their life and pursuing positive elements listed above, yet happiness cannot be increased by this process since they are two parallel states of mind. A lack of unhappiness does not automatically generate happiness to keep the balance, but rather a period of blank. The argument for what constitutes happiness discussed in the prior section is a one-way ticket that explicates &amp;ldquo;why you are happy/unhappy&amp;rdquo;, but not &amp;ldquo;how to be happy&amp;rdquo; and shall never be resorted to as a guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second phenomenon I want to discuss here is how people tend to measure happiness through both vertical and horizontal comparison. Horizontal comparison compares the self with others, stating that happiness is a manifestation of schadenfreude, where one takes pleasure in knowing that someone else lives a more desolate life than them, thus happiness is a rank determined by level of sufferings. I want to write professionally, but this is just utter bullshit. It not only rejects the empathetic nature of humanity entirely, but also interprets happiness from a superficial, materialistic, and monistic understanding in which the measurement of happiness is simplified to the amount of objective misery one has to suffer. Misery is not objective after one surpasses the element of the general environment as it is taken over by one&amp;rsquo;s mental capacity. If it is acknowledged that everyone has different physical pain tolerances, why would not it be so for mental pain too? Happiness is a concept too abstract and personal to be compared horizontally with its lack of universal rules on its measurement, and too uncorrupted to be used to bestow a sense of superiority to those who are considered &amp;ldquo;luckier&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about vertical comparison, where one compares the present self with the past self? By concerning only one subject, it agrees that happiness is personal and abandons the use of schadenfreude. Rather than the objective misery that horizontal comparison has assumed, vertical comparison focuses more on the fluidity of the mind and attempts to measure happiness through a subjective evaluation of the state of the mind at each time frame, carried out through the repetition of self-scrutiny: &amp;ldquo;are you feeling happier&amp;rdquo;. At first glance, it is similar to the goalless pursuit I have criticized in the second paragraph, yet the word &amp;ldquo;happier&amp;rdquo;, a comparative rather than its definite adjective &amp;ldquo;happy&amp;rdquo;, recognizes the pre-existence of happiness before the question is asked. The pursuit of &amp;ldquo;happierness&amp;rdquo; represents a positive mindset of building upon what is already established to get closer to the peak of happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides comparison, the concept of amor fati, or &amp;ldquo;love of fate&amp;rdquo;, has also been mentioned as an attitude for the harvest of true happiness. However, suppose  average people are virtuous enough to accept absolutely everything that life has to offer, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t we refer to them as saints? Any idealistic and heroic views of humans are not suitable as a formula for the achievement of happiness, a basic need for living that cannot be romantized. Amor fati is not the way to happiness, but to greatness. Some call it virtuous and some call it coping.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do We Still Need God?</title>
      <link>https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/post/do-we-still-need-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 09:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rein@fedora.email (rein)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/post/do-we-still-need-god/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is commonly argued that religion, or to be precise, Christianity in particular, has been declining in western civilization along with the rise of secularism and atheism. Younger generations who claim to be religious are likely to consider it part of collective identity, instead of the traditional definition of holding a belief in higher entities. One of the examples would be the debate on Jews, whether Jewish the ethnicity and culture should be separated from Judaism the religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, I am not a westerner or Christian as you have probably already known, but it is fun to look from the west&amp;rsquo;s perspective on how Christianity reached its climax and received more challenges as the west entered the Age of Reason and industrialization with more innovations on science, political ideologies and ethics. We find ourselves ask this question more often: how did we get here? Do we still need God in a modern and well-developed society? If yes, what can replace religion or should it be completely abandoned?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This long post will be classified into 4 main parts and a bonus part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What makes up a religion and why do we have it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What confrontations have religion received?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do those confrontations relate to the question on whether we still need a God?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is new in today&amp;rsquo;s world?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a future? (bonus track)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I planned to make a TL;DR but seems like there is no need because it is way too long for a TL;DR and my post isn&amp;rsquo;t that long to read. So I deleted that part. Ask for one if you want it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-i&#34;&gt;Part I&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Religion was born in parallel to human civilization and its main purpose was to direct people on the subject of nature phenomenon and morality. In simpler words, to drag people out from ignorance of our surroundings and to have something to rely on. Through fostering faith in a higher entity, religion established a complicated system dedicated to deciphering the myth of universe and setting standard rules for human behaviors. Many have also argued that it is the human instinct that guides us to depend on an omnipotent creature and to fulfill the mental emptiness, thus no explanation for the existence of religion is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the relationship between babies and parents as an analogy, humans and God are similar. We want to create a supporting figure in our life to torn off the chaos and be there when we are in need. Religion is an extension of and a solution for our insecurity and desire of being loved and connected through a divine figure. From religions we form political stability, moral coherency, and a functioning society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for nature phenomenon, the most famous example would be the Genesis story of world creation. It would be a waste of time for you and for me to repeat the story again here. Before contemporary science teachings entered the public and was integrated into part of education, God was held responsible for origins of all nature phenomenons and thus led many to argue that science and religion could not co-exist due to contradiction between objectivity and spirituality, and as science develops, religion would continue to lose its believers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morality serves as another fundamental base of every religion. Even in a more secular society, it would be easy to find people who agree that their morals are passed from their religion. In contrast to most ethnic theories developed later, theological morality completely rejects subjectivism and resorts to the divine command theory that is dependent on obedience to God&amp;rsquo;s commands. However, this theory was challenged as early as in ancient Greece, presented in Plato&amp;rsquo;s Euthyphro dilemma. During the conversation between Socrates and Euthyphro, Socrates questioned that &amp;ldquo;is the pious loved by the gods because it is pious, or is it pious because it is loved by the gods?&amp;rdquo;. It blurred the order of consequences and actions, presenting a scenario where morality is either not dependent on God or not logical due to the numerous sufferings being justified by the scapegoat of God&amp;rsquo;s will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another notable argument for theological morality is on how religious teachings preach for incentives and punishments. Compared to the divine command theory, this idea focuses more on the motivation that prompts us to follow moral guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theories on death and afterlife somehow get less recognition or have been classified as part of teachings on nature and ethics as one of the core elements of religion. Considering Christian beliefs on life after death, it appears more adequate to say that afterlife imagination should be isolated on its own. According to Luke 23.43, Jesus answered to the thief on the cross that &amp;ldquo;truly I tell you, today you will be with me in paradise&amp;rdquo;, promising an immaterial life in heaven after death. When the Day of Judgment arrives, all humanity would testify in front of God that determines whether they would be sent to heaven or hell for eternity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of an imperishable soul in an everlasting joy with God after death appeases the fear of the unknown after the physical death, providing both spiritual support and a goal of gaining virtues during life. Death is part of nature that can be perceived by sensations, yet life after death and the concept of &amp;ldquo;soul&amp;rdquo; can only be understood through thinking experiments even until today, making it an unfit candidate for the nature category. Even though the Judgment story encourages the practice of virtues, it serves merely as an instrument that preaches the benefits of following, or the underlying threats of not following Christian morals but does not directly describe the set of rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life, as opposed to death, should be equally perceived upon the same basis. The simple purpose of life according to the Bible is to trust God and to love God, yet this oversimplified definition of our seemingly elaborate life is confronted by skeptics in the modern age to be a false doctrine that shackles us from individualistic achievements and encourages abandonment of self. Despite its disappointing answer that diminishes personal values, it provides an unpretentious and modest principle for the average man that compels them to be a functioning member of society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explanation for nature, morality, and explanation for death and life form the three basic components of every religion yet the decline of religion in the modern society nonetheless proved the alternatives humans have found to replace part of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-ii&#34;&gt;Part II&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, all aspects of religions encountered confrontations in a quickly changing society. Before we dive into the new age of rationality, let&amp;rsquo;s consider this popular mind game: Do absolute truths exist? If you answer no, you are contradicting yourself since you acknowledged that &amp;ldquo;absolute truths exist&amp;rdquo; is an absolutely false statement. But if you answer yes, it applies in terms of logic but not so much in real life. Sure, absolute truths exist in a scientific world, yet do they in a moral world or in an artistic sense? Some might declare that the lack of absolute is the source of insecurities, but I would rather credit it to the conflict of absolute and non-absolute. Non-absolute provides an opportunity to examine the surrounding world or the spiritual realm from a subjective perspective, emboldening a completely personal and free interpretation. The blurred barrier between absolute and non-absolute, however, supports both a personal and a universal view, leading to endless confusion and a mayhem of possibilities and phantasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest challenge of all to the supremacy of religion, was scientific views of our surroundings. Epicurus, one of the most well-known criticizers of religion in the ancient Greece  claimed that God is not involved in the world we live in. Heavily influenced by Democritus, the other philosopher who proposed the idea of atoms being the smallest unit that composed the material universe, Epicurus further argued that souls and as well as God, two transcendent existences, are also products of atoms, diminishing the divine values held by them. Differed from humans, Gods reside in a less turbulent world that is filled by ultimate happiness, oblivious of the world we are familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the history of science in the European world centuries later, scientists&amp;rsquo; discoveries that contradicted those of the Bible were condemned of heresy by the Church. Out of them Darwin&amp;rsquo;s evolution theory and Copernicus&amp;rsquo;s heliocentric theory cast the most direct influences upon authority of Christianity. By overturning the dominating  creationism and challenging the institutionalized religion, deism gained popularity and the power of the Church declined as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The debate on religious teachings vs. scientific theories continued even in the modern society, such as the debate on whether evolution should be taught as a possible theory or a matter of facts in public schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, innovations in ethics did not end up physically under guillotines or spark political debates, yet still repudiated the divine command theory under Christianity. It is a plausible phenomenon as science presents itself as a collection of facts and claims absolute rationality while condemning religious views of the world being a product of superstition, but ethics presents itself with more diversity and acts more lenient toward alternative theories. Ethical theories that are deprived of theological foundations are able to co-exist with the Biblical directions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilitarianism, a relatively modern ethical position, argues that &amp;ldquo;actions are right in proportion as they tend to promote happiness, wrong as they tend to produce the reverse of happiness&amp;rdquo;, suggesting the subjectivism of morality as each individual obtains a unique definition of utility. In addition, the development of consequentialism ideologies contradicted the base of virtue ethics on account of its evaluation of actions rather than a set of rigid rules that takes minimum regard of the situation like the Ten Commandments. It denied humans to perform virtuous duties and presumed them to be only in pursuit of happiness yet nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correspondingly, Kant&amp;rsquo;s categorical imperative resorts to objectivism as it promotes that &amp;ldquo;act only according to that maxim by which you can at the same time will that it should become a universal law&amp;rdquo;. Similar to the divine command, Kant acknowledges an universal agent that assigns moral obligations in all circumstances, yet the authority of God has been transferred to human&amp;rsquo;s hands and ethical decisions are associated with rationality. In comparison, the social contract theory promotes for a less individualistic stand on morality, affirming a mutual agreement toward public good to claim the jurisdiction of moral decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet for meaning of death and life, we still struggle to find a satisfying answer that neither avails itself of religion nor falls into the trap of nihilism. It almost serves as the retaliation from God to punish the humans for their ambition to build yet another Tower of Babel to not only reach the heaven, but also to chant the atheistic anthem directly into God&amp;rsquo;s face and to tell him that we no longer need him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ernest Becker&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Denial of Death&lt;/em&gt;, a book that focuses on the reason behind existence and the fear of death, concludes that humans are vulnerable from accepting the truth of mortality and embrace artificial immortality through forming identities in order to engage in cultural groups, or be bounded to a social contract. The mythical hero system attempts to establish immortal figures that solve the existential dilemma and to provide a solution for the meaningless life. As one of the worst consequences, humans would resort to deprecation of intellect through &amp;ldquo;tranquilizing itself with the trivial&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becker is not the only one who proclaimed the human need to establish group solidarity and to affirm collective consciousness. Durkheim, a prominent sociologist, credited the agent that facilitates this process to religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another famous critique of religion would be our all-time pop culture&amp;rsquo;s favorite philosopher Nietzsche, whose &amp;ldquo;God is dead&amp;rdquo; became a classic of the classics. Nietzsche suggested that the atheistic industrial age sacrificed religion and was questing after science. Religion or mainly Christianity, has no purpose other than preserving the human race by educating the mass on worshiping &amp;ldquo;weakness&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sickness&amp;rdquo;. The idea of sufferings endured during the material life being rewarded in afterlife corrupted the European minds and endorsed mediocrity. However, the replacement by science did not provide any positive faith, thus leading to another round of endless pessimism. Abolition of God and its system syllabified a new age of skepticism and rationality, fostering the belief in deism and a long period of spiritual blank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the challenges from miscellaneous perspectives including the vitalization of scientific reasoning and encouragement of rationality during the Enlightenment, developments of ethical theories apart from theology, and the rise of idea that religion is no more than a social contract that unites human for accomplishments of common good and desensitizes our resistance toward doctrines God preaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the question is, are they powerful enough to take down God and worship logic instead? Or are we stuck in the Garden of Earthly Delights and fail to escape from our ignorance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-iii&#34;&gt;Part III&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decline of religion is a gradual process resembling the fall of an empire. It is not practicable to pinpoint an exact point of history and declare it to be the day that God bid farewell, nor has it a precise definition on what it refers to by &amp;ldquo;decline&amp;rdquo;. Therefore, to identify the source of decline, it is necessary to define it beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should have noticed that the title of this post is called &amp;ldquo;Do We Still Need God?&amp;rdquo;, but not &amp;ldquo;Do We Still Need Religion?&amp;rdquo;, yet before this section we have treated them as interchangeable objects even though they are not. God is the omnipresent and omnipotent being that can manifest himself without religion as a supplementary or prerequisite, while religion is a reconciliation with God that serves as the mediator between God and humans, that cannot be independent and would perish once the concept of God is lost. Correspondingly, the decline of God symbolizes a loss of faith in one or more higher beings that transcend humans both physically and mentally, while the decline of religion merely symbolizes the gradual disappearance of traditional methods humans utilized to worship God. Thus by comparison, the decline of God has a greater impact on humanity in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worship of science and logic originated from the Enlightenment contributed greatly to the decline of religion, yet preserved God&amp;rsquo;s seat. Thomas Paine in his book &lt;em&gt;The Age of Reason&lt;/em&gt; in which the criticism drawn on religious institutions and fallacies present in the Bible popularized deism in Europe and America, did not negate the existence of God but simply stated that God does not interfere with humanity. To speak of this in a practical sense, many scientists have identified themselves as religious despite a lower percentage than the general public. Contradictory to what some people have believed, in spite of the incompatibility between science and religion from a rational perspective, religion, or just a higher entity in general, provides metaphysical and psychological support to an individual independent from physical laws and chemical formulas that shape the material world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To argue it further, the collapse of creationism and biblical myths itself holds little importance. It is the rise of rationality and the signal of a less credulous age that threatens God&amp;rsquo;s existence and motivates latter generations to maintain a skeptical attitude toward those that cannot be proved. Speaking more radically, once God&amp;rsquo;s existence is proved through scientific reasoning, God will too be part of the science and religion, an empty shell,  will be abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of rationality demonstrates itself again in the development of morality. Ivan Karamazov, a compromised atheist in the novel &lt;em&gt;The Brothers Karamazov&lt;/em&gt;, is tortured by the contradiction of his belief in God and God&amp;rsquo;s failure to comply with his moral standard. All the innocent sufferings in this world cannot be justified if God is as what religion has portrayed, merciful and shares an universal love toward mankind. Simple logic could not satisfyingly fill this gap: if God does not care about mankind and does not engage in human activities, does it even matter if we deny the existence of God completely? If God left human on their own after the creation of world and never listened to our prayers, do we still need to care about and worship a so-called God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though Ivan displays his distrust in religion, he still believes in superintendence by morality imposed by Christianity. Thus in a godless world, morality and laws would be lost as a consequence due to the lack of directions and punishments. However, the argument for rationality proves humans to be capable of thinking freely and to make reasonable ethic choices without receiving commands. God in a moral sense could be replaced by a more objective and logical being, humans themselves in the case of utilitarianism and categorical imperatives, and a set of contracts in the case of social contract theory. The transform of sovereignty cannot be used to validate the decline of God, but can instead be used to obviate the necessity of a God. Once virtues cease to be the only rules that regulate morality, an all-virtuous being is destined to tolerate a depreciation in its value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the volatile characteristic of societal standards rises objections to the static doctrines preached by religion. However, this is irrelevant to God as his words are often open to misinterpretation and manipulation for political goals, thus reducing the statement to be a critique of personal evaluations yet not religion or God as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once our trip ends at the material realm, the triumph of rationality transforms into the empty defense of nothingness. Humans realize that rationality is not the panacea that can magically run the world. This is the point we ask ourselves and fall into a paradox: are we truly rational animals? If we are rational, we will not be in denial of death and establish an immortal utopia through abstract concepts or try to bestow a meaning to the meaningless life we live; if we are irrational, we will happily continue our tradition of relegating to God&amp;rsquo;s power and follow his words as guidance to live an unquestioned and basic life. The truth is, irrationality compels us to be always in pursuit of a heroic life and a respectable death, while rationality denies the possibility of such romanticism in a harsh reality where atoms dictate the order. The collision of two distinct ideologies result in a state of chaos in which we constantly contradict ourselves and come to the nihilistic conclusion that nothing after all is permanent, therefore neither life nor death has an objective meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this section, the word &amp;ldquo;rationality&amp;rdquo; has been emphasized and is utilized as vindication for the diminishing influence of God over humanity. Therefore, the general culture whose goal is to evangelize its citizens into disciples of logic could only substantiate an omnipotent being that cannot be substantiated through evacuation of their faith to a higher realm, free from sovereignty of scientific laws that trammel our vision and imagination by facts. God is the solution and the ultimate compromise to the quandary above and to our evolutionary ineptitude as an organism with an anarchic mind. One may possibly argue that certain components of a religion are products of fictionalized idealism that speak unreasonableness, but no one except an absolute atheist could safely assume that God is part of the irrationality that humanity should abandon attributable to the impossibility of confirming or negating of an existence outside of the known reality. Recognition of such a being automatically acknowledges a space beyond the finite and perishable life that promises a state higher than nothingness once the physical body reaches its limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reaching this conclusion, it is not surprising to identify the pattern of finding God when an individual undergoes a life threatening situation or depression. Irrationality becomes the Noah&amp;rsquo;s Ark once the faith in rationality dwindles, whose relationship can be defined as inversely proportional. What else is there to rely on if the rational answer provided by reality is a hard-to-swallow pill? It must be an entity that is free from the restrain of reality yet does not directly contradict our innate rationality. In this sense, I might have to partially agree with Marx on his statement &amp;ldquo;religion is the opium of the people&amp;rdquo;. It mitigates the brutality present by life and produces permanent relief, in contrast to the temporary joy of drugs and alcohol shackled by their inescapability from the material realm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to go deep into the philosophy of existentialism, but as well as the shift of power in morality, the triumph of individualism returns the collective purpose formed under religion back to each individual&amp;rsquo;s own hands, as to allow a personalized rationale for the meaning of life. Religion used to be the pillar of the society according to Durkheim, yet the development of movements that advocated for free expression of self whether in the field of art, music, literature, or politics, have alleviated the luxurious need of a meticulous system by transferring the responsibility from worships of a higher entity to worships of humanity. We might need God in a metaphysical sense, but not while  the physical body is still completing its journey in the material world as the amount of possibilities enumerated in front of us eliminated the submissive option of letting God define the &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the age of individualism, where humanity celebrates the myth of free-from-the-society independence. The question of &amp;ldquo;does God exist&amp;rdquo; has already morphed into the question of &amp;ldquo;do we need a God&amp;rdquo; during the rise of skepticism and rationalism in which we admit that it is impossible to prove the existence or nonexistence of God. Yet henceforth a new question has been asked to be pondered: what defines God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-iv&#34;&gt;Part IV&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As past glories of religions faded into modern celebration of rationality and individualism, contemporary religions that aim to fuse all teachings of worldwide religions into one and acknowledge the achievements of humanity have emerged as a result, while the Baha&amp;rsquo;i faith being one of them. This distinctive new universal religion claims that all religious doctrines drafted by God&amp;rsquo;s messengers, or the manifestation of God, state true yet incomplete. The goal of Baha&amp;rsquo;i is thus to solve the puzzle of God&amp;rsquo;s words by uniting all religions and to establish an unifying vision of the future. Faiths in the oneness of humanity also encourage its believers to promote for &amp;ldquo;fundamental equality of the sexes, the harmony between religion and science, the centrality of justice to all human endeavors&amp;rdquo;, in my interpretation echos certain ideas presented in political ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking from a modern perspective, the politicization of individuals and polarization of political ideals almost drove politics to one of the candidates for alternatives of religion. In a secular society dominated by secular culture, younger generations seek spiritual comfort in political activism as it endorses a collective identity and institutes an ambition higher than self to satisfy the need for a general purpose of life. The emphasis on the optimistic aspect of contemporary activism that we are all able to change the world sets up the never-materialized illusion of a permanently progressing future, replacing the belief in God and minimizing the fear of uncertainty that has always shadowed humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous section, we have come to the conclusion that God only displays importance in elevating self spiritually to a higher dimension and to provide mental assuagement from material pain inflicted by the world, yet this theory is also challenged by the rising partisan politics, specifically from the left whose idealism on equality and visualization of a society that embraces originality and non-conformity that has attracted young people to be part of the crusade against outdated traditional standards. Instead of wasting our innate irrationality on a higher entity, why not spending it on dreaming a utopia? A thing that can be imagined, be possible through our own effort, and be &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politics on its own is not convincing enough for the evidence of God&amp;rsquo;s definition being blurred. The evolving technology would be the main protagonist in the transformation of our perception. One obvious example would be transhumanism and its possible implementation through genetic engineering, in which serves as a manifestation of humanity&amp;rsquo;s ambition to alter the unalterable, and to strengthen the predetermined. Despite the controversy regarding moral practice, humans have never ceased researches on the feasibility of producing superhumans. The myth of creationism has been debunked and is widely rejected by the new generation, yet respect toward a natural way of living is still preserved in some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to what some may argue, it is not the realization of post-human that will lead to the extinction of belief in God, but the idea of the attempt to realize post-human itself. By hypothesizing the possibility of manufacturing a more advanced race utilizing technology, humans have shattered the fantasy of God being the only creator behind the universe, reinforcing the statement that humans possess the privilege and the right to reverse or redesign the already designated path by a divine being. This new attitude toward the power of creation facilitates the collective recognition of humanity being on an equivalent position with God. We can quickly take a peek at this logic dilemma with syllogism:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If something is God, it is defined to be a supreme being with the power to create and change other beings.
And if something is defined to be a supreme being with the power to create and change inferior beings, it is human.
God is human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boom. Perfectly phrased sophistry right there despite multiple major flaws in this proof. The antecedent premise is already an incomplete thus false statement, making the entire proof nothing more than a mind game. It could be  debunked by the following invalid proof:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Gods are supreme beings with the power to create and change other beings.
All humans are supreme beings with the power to create and change other beings.
God is human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this mind game is merely a placebo for the rising threat of God being murdered the second time after Nietzsche. I am only trying to disapprove with the statement of humanity being ready to claim the same high ground as God in respect of power of creation, but not to negate the already established mindset of the young generation that champions the speculation of technology aiding humanity to be the new God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another notable achievement of technology would be internet, which I ironically refer to as the product of virtual creationism. We might have missed the opportunity to collaborate on the Earth project with God, but we managed to conceptualize a virtual world inside the material world, both as a form of escapism in standards nowadays and provocation toward the belief mentioned above that only God possesses the power to create. Internet, a convoluted network actualized through seemingly abstract protocols that facilitates the flow of information and minimizes the distance of communication, is argued to be a revolutionary force in the tech world that has cast dramatic influences over humanity. It does not physically interact with the reality we now perceive, but it is indeed a legitimate &amp;ldquo;world&amp;rdquo; that functions on the foundation of basic rules and almost resembles a secret garden for we, Mary Lennox, to soothe our sour temper on dissatisfaction of the reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how does internet redefine God? If the ideology of transhumanism is the shadow of a dream we chase after, then internet is a realized dream that has already matured and conquered our old lives. An unrealized ideology only psychologically transforms our perception, yet a materialized and a perfectly accomplished new &amp;ldquo;world&amp;rdquo; obtains the potentiality of reshaping the dominating worldview. We are the creators, and each one of us can be gods on the internet. God is no longer divine and lost the honor to be capitalized as the word &amp;ldquo;god&amp;rdquo; does not refer to a particular holy figure as what monotheism has suggested. Every netizen holds the power to modify elements of the internet, or to create yet another virtual land or virtual self within it. It is constantly evolving, with no restrictions by physics, laws, or nature that manifests a factor of uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is &amp;ldquo;God&amp;rdquo; after all if humanity can all be &amp;ldquo;gods&amp;rdquo;? Or is the invention of internet another bubble that will soon be proved to be fragile like how the rationality movement has transformed into the age of nihilism? Or does the myth of &amp;ldquo;The One&amp;rdquo; no longer holds true as we claimed his magic? One could argue that internet is not real and thus does not threaten the existence of God, but wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be a questionable assertion since you can&amp;rsquo;t say for certain that God is real either?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would rather leave these questions unanswered. They are reserved for the future and I&amp;rsquo;d love to see what answer time would give us. The war between rationality and God has entered a new phase, and before we jump into it, just remember this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no need for a God if we are the gods, no need for a heaven if we can build a heaven on our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bonus&#34;&gt;Bonus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main part of the post is supposed to end here yet I have been thinking about the new role of God in a post-modern world after talking to a friend ~who almost talked like a psychopath~. What if we take this arrogance one step further? Remember the mind game in the beginning of the second section? It is ultimately a mind game and the rise of deconstruction has ruptured the existence of any absolute truths. God is not an exception to the deconstruction view of the world. As an assumed absolute and everlasting entity, it is impossible to deconstruct it and to gain a relative insight from its components since it can only be perceived as a whole. God is either structureless and does not exist, or it does not adhere to the conservative interpretation and exists in multiple forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovational and revolutionary, but this is taking it too far if you ask me. It is fascinating to think about how we the homo sapiens have transformed from pure irrationality and blind idolatry of God to pure rationality and blind idolatry of science, but somehow fell back to pure irrationality and blind idolatry of (?). The only difference is that, this time we are fully aware of our irrationality and celebrate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did we reach a limit or are we still going? To be continued&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, &amp;ldquo;Do We Still Need God&amp;rdquo; is clearly asking for a boolean value but I didn&amp;rsquo;t give one yet. You would be probably disappointed if all I give you is a vague &amp;ldquo;oh umm kinda I guess?&amp;rdquo; after this read, so I am going to give you a real answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least in a modern and a post modern sense. God has way too many replacements even though some of them are fast food tier options. We have rejected God over and over again despite our past need for him as to escape from the brutal reality, and therefore it would be an egoistic decision to drag him back yet mocks his inability to perform the duty of &amp;ldquo;God&amp;rdquo; in the traditional interpretation. There is no going back ever since the lessened emphasis on collective identity and the rise of individualism, pushing away God who claims to be absolute in a field that no one could claim to be absolute. This is indeed a depressing age and the age of &amp;ldquo;entertaining ourselves to death&amp;rdquo;, but you can&amp;rsquo;t do anything. History cannot be rewritten and you cannot force anyone to believe in a being that has endured from skepticism for centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could have also argued that the answer &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo; is my own cope to the decline of God, but not an universal answer that represents this generation. However, is there really an objective answer? I highly doubt it. After all, competing ideologies have provided numerous choices what to believe and where to obtain an ultimate &amp;ldquo;meaning&amp;rdquo;. Whether speaking from a secular or non-secular perspective, God is not a necessary component of the so-called &amp;ldquo;process&amp;rdquo; to today&amp;rsquo;s world and we have already graduated from relying on theology to explain everything or to cure pain. As what I have narcissistically said, God is a compromise for the battle between irrationality and rationality, but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be the God we have imagined from the imagery produced by religion. It can be anyone or anything. Trees and grass, you and me. Anything that maintains a meaning out of the meaninglessness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will doom scroll, you will cope with pessimism, you will not need a God, and you will be happy. Thank you for listening to an atheist&amp;rsquo;s gibberish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Talk About Sympathy</title>
      <link>https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/post/lets-talk-about-sympathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 21:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rein@fedora.email (rein)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/post/lets-talk-about-sympathy/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about the emotion “sympathy” recently and came up with this sophistry tier post. It is like a messy shower thought rather than a sophisticated theory that needs 2000 words to explain, but I am still going to put it here since I feel like I am obligated to update this blog at least once a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sympathy, an emotion that involves acknowledgement and pitiness toward another individual’s sorrow, is often confused with the word empathy. I am not a walking dictionary so my explanation won’t be perfect, but I will share my understanding here. There are two parts that make the words differ. The first is that sympathy is an act of receiving and reacting, while empathy is an act of receiving and echoing; and the second is that sympathy can only be displayed via pitiness for one another’s experience, while empathy can be displayed in any forms of emotion as long as it corresponds to one another’s experience. In short, sympathy is composed of one emotion (pitiness for others’sorrow) and empathy is a group of emotions (sorrowful for others’sorrow, happy for others’ happiness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I am only going to talk about sympathy. This word has been ignored for long since people learned the existence of empathy. You could argue that sympathy is not really an emotion, but I would disagree with that since it is still &amp;ldquo;an instinctive feeling that could possibly effect your mind and behavior&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Differing from most of the other emotions, sympathy is an emotion that can only be experienced through others and thus maintains neutrality. Picture your mind as a scale with one side being positive and one side being negative. When you encounter an event that triggers anger, sadness, or fear, it would add more weight to the negative side of the scale. On the other hand, joy, confidence, or gratitude would be a plus for the positive side of the scale. Sympathy on its own does not cause postive or negative mood swing, since it is not an emotion directly triggered from a personal experience. If one has a lasting mood change due to others’ experiences, I would rather call it empathy than sympathy because in cases of sympathy, you do not share the feeling with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This special property of sympathy allows it to be the most “affordable” emotion in my opinion. You can easily pay it to people, and people can also pay it easily to you. The affordability of sympathy makes this emotion rather powerless as its influence on people is minimal and temporary. Internet also facilitates this process and further weakens the power of sympathy. Everyone can type “I’m sorry to hear that” or “oh that’s too bad” in the comment section as a reaction to a sad post. However, how many of you are really feeling sorry? Your life plot will stay the same no matter if you say sorry and make that surprising expression to the news of your neighbors losing their cats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I admit that I am taking the moral high ground and being a misanthrope to those who are just trying to be nice, but that is what I am proving here. Humans are not Jesus. At least l can’t love everyone equally or center my thoughts around people outside of my circle. Even though you cannot wholeheartedly relate to someone else’s misery, you can still express your sympathy, demonstrating the convenience and casualness of it. By showing concern, or allowing me to say this, faking concern toward others, one is not going to gain or lost anything. To the opposite side who is receiving, your sympathy can be helpful to a certain extent or completely negligible under some circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypocrite is a word often linked with fake sympathy. By definition, hypocrite is “a person who puts on a false appearance of virtue or religion”. However, if you take it to an extreme, every functioning human can be labeled as a hypocrite due to the education we have received since childhood on the significance of symphasizing with one another. In many cases, We send messages of sympahty as an uncounscious reaction but not as a display of virtue. I am not saying that the emotion of sympathy is not real and artificial. I actually consider it the opposite way. It is the neutrality and the affordability of sympathy that diminishes the value of it but it does exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empathy shouod be a prerequisite for sympathy. Without understanding and sharing feelings with the receiving side, one cannot fully develop pitiness. The lack of mutual understanding restrains the giving side from feeling pitiful. We are more likely to empathize with people who are close to us or those who share similar experiences, followed by stronger sympathy that is caused by a negative mood change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I have argued that the effect of sympathy can be minimal and sometimes leads to hypocrisy, I would still encourage everyone to take the habit of sympathizing. It helps form the bond in our society to maintain peace and to promote the concept of love. Sympathy also builds up respect and dignity. Properly reacting to other human beings’ emotions is a polite way to exhibit your respect toward them, while proving yourself to be capable of caring and giving. It is the basic manner on treating others and the backbone of communication,  which should thus be followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short lesson here: be a moral person and don’t act like a cold psychopath because it is cool. You can still show your sympathy even if there is an unbreakable A.T. field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Peace &amp; Love&#34;, Self-censorship, and the Future of Social Media</title>
      <link>https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/post/peace-and-love-self-censorship-and-the-future-of-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 17:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rein@fedora.email (rein)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.midnight-rain.xyz/post/peace-and-love-self-censorship-and-the-future-of-social-media/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been following up on news recently (well, maybe not that recent), you might have already heard an overwhelming amount of reports that concerns censorship involving Trump ban; removal of Parler, a right wing social media platform that gains reputation during Capitol riots; removal of &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;When Harry became Sally&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, a controversial book criticized for its transphobia; and the most recent one is the removal of Dr. Seuss&amp;rsquo;s six books that &amp;ldquo;portray people in ways that are hurtful and wrong&amp;rdquo; according to Dr. Seuss Enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relying on its tremendous amount of users across the globe, Big Tech is deprecated for its monopolization of tech industry and deprivation of free speech. After realizing this ugly truth of modern social media, many users have decided to move to alternative self-hosted platforms such as mastodon and therefore have learned the concept of decentralization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am indeed in opposition with Big Tech, who demonstrates its manipulation of voices through censorship of different views. However, I can&amp;rsquo;t quite agree with the opinion that a fully decentralized social media will create a censorship-free zone for people to utilize their freedom of speech. Yes, decentralization is helping, but not hundred percent. Big Tech is a problem, but it might be too late to eliminate them and to restore a platform where all these account suspension, shadow ban, cancel culture etc. are merely words that sound like a bad meme. This is what I want to talk about here: &lt;strong&gt;how the &amp;ldquo;Peace &amp;amp; Love&amp;rdquo; propaganda encourages self-censorship and why I am pessimistic about the future of social media.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be my bias, but when I think of propaganda, the only thing that comes into my mind is the government. Even if the media and tech companies are the ones that spread the propaganda, I still consider them a puppet of the government who serve as the messenger rather than the director. It has never occurred to me that &lt;strong&gt;corporations can function entirely independent of the government while developing into a certain size that allows it to acquire supremacy in which resembles a second government&lt;/strong&gt; as you can see from the Trump ban incident. Due to people&amp;rsquo;s innate distrust of the government, the potential risk involved in those corporations could be more harmful and harder to spot in most situations. In addition to that, the biased information they hope their audiences to believe does not really echo the &amp;ldquo;definition of propaganda&amp;rdquo; from your education on Nazi propaganda in your middle school history class. This strange type of propaganda from corporations, who are mostly controlled by the liberals or tend to gain benefits from promoting liberal ideologies, is what I would like to call &amp;ldquo;Peace &amp;amp; Love&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t find a combination of words that summarizes liberal ideologies as well as peace and love, considering that social equality, egalitarianism, and justice are the three main themes of it. liberals in the US have been active in resistance against racism, sexism, homophobia, etc. and tend to encourage more aggressive immigration policies and to support &amp;ldquo;minority communities&amp;rdquo; such as the LGBTQ group. At first glance, &lt;strong&gt;it is hard to notice any incoherence in liberals&amp;rsquo; ideologies, since they resonate the preamble of American Constitution in which all men are created equal and depict an utopian society free of hate or conflicts.&lt;/strong&gt; But here the question comes: how do we define the boundary between hate and regular expression? We have been told to uphold the &amp;ldquo;Peace &amp;amp; Love&amp;rdquo; ideology, but explanations liberals provide us are either ambiguous paraphrases that link back to their statements or contradictions that eventually lead to more confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I will provide my own brief definition of &amp;ldquo;hate&amp;rdquo;: clear hostility displayed toward a certain group or individual. The keywords here are &amp;ldquo;hostility&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;displayed&amp;rdquo;. Stereotype is not hate, neither are &amp;ldquo;offensive sounding&amp;rdquo; jokes or thoughts inside your head. I do understand that everyone has their own definition of hate, and everyone has their own trigger words. &lt;strong&gt;What I do not understand is that how everything can be labeled as &amp;ldquo;hate&amp;rdquo; nowadays and how liberals use &amp;ldquo;justice for all&amp;rdquo; as an excuse to censor the entire internet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The invention of &amp;ldquo;cultural appropriation&amp;rdquo; is a perfect example for my point. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know this word, it means &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;the adoption of an element or elements of one culture or identity by members of another culture or identity that can be controversial when members of a dominant culture appropriate from disadvantaged minority cultures&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; according to wikipedia. It&amp;rsquo;s quite lengthy, but the basic meaning I have grepped is that using elements from other culture can be offending sometimes if they don&amp;rsquo;t represent their original meanings. For example, a white girl, a member of &amp;ldquo;dominant culture&amp;rdquo;, can be accused of cultural appropriation for wearing kimono because she doesn&amp;rsquo;t display enough knowledge of Japanese culture. I think that the concept of cultural appropriation is intended to increase respect for cultures one is not familiar with, but in practice, it is the sudo word for completely inaccurate accusation of discrimination and somehow accomplishes the inverse of its original purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of liberal&amp;rsquo; attempt to serve justice for &amp;ldquo;repressive minority groups&amp;rdquo;, majority groups become the new target of discrimination. It is almost a trend now for mainstream media to ask for white people&amp;rsquo;s apology for their skin color, or to ask &amp;ldquo;cisgender&amp;rdquo; (a person whose sense of personal identity and gender corresponds with their birth sex) to use pronouns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The illusion of an ideal society, the fanatical obsession of &amp;ldquo;equality&amp;rdquo;, and a distorted understanding of mutual respect set the standards for &amp;ldquo;Peace &amp;amp; Love&amp;rdquo; ideologies and further developed into liberal propaganda&lt;/strong&gt;. Just as you can see from Amazon&amp;rsquo;s removal of &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;When Harry became Sally&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, corporations are the ones who determine what the mass can believe, and the disciples of &amp;ldquo;Peace &amp;amp; Love&amp;rdquo; idodelogy are the ones who will support it from the botttom of their hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the help from Big Tech, &amp;ldquo;Peace $ Love&amp;rdquo; ideology dominates mainstream social media nowadays. Any opposite opinion is likely to be reported for &amp;ldquo;violating the company&amp;rsquo;s policy&amp;rdquo;. But would social media improve off Big Techs&amp;rsquo; hands? Only if the mass stops voluntary self-regulation of their own views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;the Washington University in St. Louis study&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;self-censorship is more common among women (43%) than among men (37%); more common in metro areas (42%) than in non-metro areas (33%); more common among those with only a high school degree (34%) and at least some college (45%) than among those with no high school diploma (27%)&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. This is a shocking set of data as almost half of the US regularly censors oneself, while those who possess high levels of education are even more likely to do so. The study credits to &amp;ldquo;growing affective political polarization&amp;rdquo; for this abnormal phenomenon, and I can quite agree with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because people so dislike each other and detest each other’s views and values, they perceive a great cost associated with sharing their opinions publicly, for little or no reward.Therefore, they keep their mouths shut and refrain from expressing their true views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did some research but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a good demographic profile for liberals in the US. Liberals make up the largest share of Democratic voters so I think it is safe to use the demographic of democrats to find correlations between political belief and the likability to self-censor. According to this &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;post&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;democrats dominate the more populated, urban centers (60%); attract more women (37%) than men (27%); are more likely to have post-graduate degrees or no high school diploma&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. It is interesting to see how it almost overlaps the data from the self-censorship study, as both data sets mention a higher percentage of those who are female, reside in urban areas, and have received high education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, we can say that &lt;strong&gt;liberal ideologies tend to encourage more self-censorship due to its promotion of social justice, in which one is likely to keep silent on sensitive topics in order to avoid potential offense to their opponent&lt;/strong&gt;. The &amp;ldquo;Peace &amp;amp; Love&amp;rdquo; propaganda influences a majority of its believers to not only be cautious when expressing their views under censorship from other entities, but also when no restriction is present. To dodge that &amp;ldquo;hate&amp;rdquo; label and not to be ostracized from the group, many have decided to shut their mouth. People can never be free if they deny to accept their own opinions and instead follow the rules for respect obediently just to not accidentally shout out the trigger words. Linking back to what I have said earlier, &lt;strong&gt;decentralization liberates us from Big Tech, but the only one who can liberate us from our mind is ourselves&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a sad truth to say that a lot of people have been locked up by &amp;ldquo;Peace &amp;amp; Love&amp;rdquo; ideology that they are unable to say, or even further, unable to see or listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the development of internet, people are able to publish their ideas and interact with people from the globe on social media. But the concerning thing of social media, apart from censorship from corporations who own the platform, is self-censorship I have mentioned. Despite freedom from Big Tech, many users of alternative social media still tend to limit what they can see or say. The most famous one among them is known as the fediverse, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;an ensemble of federated servers that are used for web publishing and file hosting, but which, while independently hosted, can communicate with each other&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, according to wikipedia. It is a decentralized social media in simpler words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some people have taken the advantage from fediverse to freely express their opinions, a group of people did not appreciate this opportunity and turned fediverse into fedisolo by starting fediblock, a list of instances they recommend other instance administrators to block due to reasons like spam, hate speech, or without any reason. There is clearly no third party involved in the creation of fediblock and it is a self-initiated movement to bring censorship to fediverse. But since administrators cannot directly ban accounts from other instances, the only thing they can accomplish to show their disapproval of different opinions is to call everyone a &amp;ldquo;Nazi&amp;rdquo;. I used to promote fediverse as a place free of censorship to my Twitter friends until one person wrote to me a 800 word sophisticated response on why I am an asshole who takes no responsibility in my words. He argues that freedom of speech is still at the hands of administrators, therefore I have no right to say such thing. He got a point, even though his attitude is terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said that I am pessimistic about the future of social media even if it is decentralized, and I think it is better to classify the uniqueness of social media before I explain my reason on feeling this way. &lt;strong&gt;A social media is a platform for different people to exchange ideas and is intended to facilitate this process by its &amp;ldquo;real time interaction&amp;rdquo; feature, while other internet platforms might not necessitate interaction with one another&lt;/strong&gt;. To simplify it even further, &lt;strong&gt;we are dependent on each other when it comes to censorship in social media while having the option to be independent on other internet platforms&lt;/strong&gt;. You can argue that self-hosted instance would be a solution to the dependency problem for the fediverse example, but do realize that other instances still have the power to block you, which is the equivalent for alienation. The point of social media is to establish relationship with each other, and the presence of censorship prevents this to happen. This is the unspoken rule of any decentralized social media: &lt;strong&gt;self censor or get out&lt;/strong&gt;, as we can see from fediverse that a majority of pleroma instances are blocked by mastodon instances for various reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not possible for social media to regain freedom of speech unless its users realize the importance of free speech and stop self-censoring. &lt;strong&gt;As long as people are still using &amp;ldquo;*&amp;rdquo; to replace words they find &amp;ldquo;inappropriate&amp;rdquo;, blocking everyone apart from those who share their opinions, consider everything as hate speech, or losing their mind on politically incorrect yet harmless jokes, we will never have a free social media regardless of decentralization&lt;/strong&gt;. Otherwise, we will all be an isolated island from each other and nothing of this reflects the definition of social media or foreseeing an optimistic future. The impact &amp;ldquo;Love &amp;amp; Peace&amp;rdquo; ideologies have done on people is irreversible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in the end, I still hope one day we can have a large-scale social media free of any form of censorship. See you freedom, someday, somewhere!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
